#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/henry-xing (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

IT Service Management
Data Centers
SDLC

# Henry Xing

Sr PM, Portfolio Management, PMP, MBA, Certified Scrum Master, SDLC, Banking, Infrastructure, Cyber Security, Cloud & Data Center Migration, PPM, JIRA, ITIL, DBA, Data Architect

Edison, New Jersey, United States

# Summary

Working Experience Summary (MBA, PMP, CSM, ITIL, DBA, JIRA)

Banking, Finance, Technology Products, and Domain,

- Portfolio Management, Integration, Transformation, Migration, Cyber Security Projects, and Program
- Global Project and Program Management (time and resource)
- Business, Technology, and Service (delivery, relationship, and support) management
- IT Security and Risk Management (Assessment and Mitigation)

Specialties: Project, Program and Portfolio Management tools - GovernX, Looker, CA Clarity PPM, Smartsheet, Open Work Bench, Confluence, JIRA, MS Project, project Quality control/assurance Tools and Technics, sizing, cost and budgeting determination, concept development, business cases, and analysis, database administration, security analysis, service quality delivery, and support, IBM ETL/Congos/Data Stage, Information security and risk management, IBM Rational Rose / SDLC / ITIL

## Experience

Verizon Vendor Portfolio Manager June 2020 - Present (2 years 11 months) Basking Ridge, New Jersey, United States

Portfolio Management

Bank Of New York Mellon Financial Corporation Limited Sr Project/Program Manager March 2017 - Present (6 years 2 months)

Cyber Security Project/Program Management

MetLife

Sr Program Manager

March 2011 - June 2015 (4 years 4 months)

Enterprise Infrastructure & Architect Program Management

**HSBC** 

Global Project Manager

June 2001 - December 2010 (9 years 7 months)

Relationship and Delivery Management - On-boarding / planning / delivering / deploying infrastructure and technology solution projects and programs including the integration, re-engineering and transformation of business processes crossing all banking business lines.

Service Support - Streamlining on-boarding strategies and delivering best practice standards and templates as well as budgeting and monitoring the qualities, expenditures and costs against delivered and realized benefits; engaging instance and change management processes as well to improve the global and local regional quality and change controls to be compliant with all relevant internal and external rules.

Goldman Sachs

Sr Data Architect

July 2000 - April 2001 (10 months)

Planed and facilitated data management initiatives, and managed project teams, in an extended process mapping, to support database driven applications in Invest Banking, Finance, Risk Management, Placement and Infrastructure business areas

Supported Investment Banking databases, high availability architecture and deployment of oracle platforms and services;

Conducted database projects' proof of concept and feasibility study along with the major spending investment banking programs;

Directed database and data architect teams (onshore and offshore) through all phases of the RDBMS technology life cycle, including requirements definition, releases, high availability architecture design, data conversion, migrations and testing;

**TD Waterhouse** 

Sr DBA / Data Architect (AVP) April 1998 - June 2000 (2 years 3 months)

Led projects to support and improve the corporate PeopleSoft Customer Relationship and Management System as well as various vendor ERP systems valuation.

Reviewed and approve database changes to support application changes per SDLC.

Created and maintained departmental procedures, including auditing and IT security policies, as data architect of firm wise infrastructure.

### Education

Rutgers University–New Brunswick
Master of Business Administration - MBA, Finance, General · (2006 - 2009)

Rutgers Business School MBA, Finance (2006 - 2008)

The City University of New York MS, Civil Engineering (1994 - 1996)

Wuhan University of Technology BS, Civil Engineering · (1986 - 1990)